<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-05T16:07:40+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ishan’s Apps</title><subtitle>Ishan is an Entrepreneur, ex-FAANG with interests in Generative AI, Blockchain, RPA, Chrome Exts..</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Premium Chrome Extensions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/05/premium-chrome-extensions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Premium Chrome Extensions" /><published>2023-05-05T16:05:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-05-05T16:05:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/05/premium-chrome-extensions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/05/premium-chrome-extensions.html"><![CDATA[<p>Sure, here are ten popular Chrome extensions that offer a paid or premium version:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Grammarly - A writing assistant tool that checks for spelling, grammar, and punctuation errors. The premium version offers advanced grammar and contextual spelling suggestions, among other features.</li>
  <li>Adblock Plus - An ad blocker that lets users block intrusive ads and pop-ups. The premium version allows for advanced customization options and additional filtering features.</li>
  <li>LastPass - A password manager that securely stores and autofills login credentials. The premium version offers additional features such as emergency access and priority customer support.</li>
  <li>Honey - A coupon-finding extension that automatically applies discounts at checkout. The premium version offers more advanced savings options and cashback rewards.</li>
  <li>Momentum - A personalized dashboard that displays a to-do list, weather forecast, and inspirational quotes. The premium version offers additional customization options and features such as focus mode and productivity tracking.</li>
  <li>Evernote Web Clipper - A note-taking and organizing tool that lets users save web pages and images. The premium version offers additional storage, search functionality, and collaboration features.</li>
  <li>Pushbullet - A notification syncing extension that displays phone notifications on a computer. The premium version offers larger file transfers and additional messaging features.</li>
  <li>Pocket - A read-it-later tool that lets users save articles and videos to view offline. The premium version offers advanced search and filtering options and a permanent library of saved items.</li>
  <li>Todoist - A task manager that helps users track and organize their to-do lists. The premium version offers additional features such as reminders, labels, and project templates.</li>
  <li>Enhancer for YouTube - A YouTube extension that offers features such as ad blocking, dark mode, and custom playback speed. The premium version offers additional features such as video downloading and channel filtering.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sure, here are ten popular Chrome extensions that offer a paid or premium version:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ishan’s Apps!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/05/04/welcome-to-ishandutta2007.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ishan’s Apps!" /><published>2023-05-04T06:41:54+05:30</published><updated>2023-05-04T06:41:54+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/05/04/welcome-to-ishandutta2007</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/05/04/welcome-to-ishandutta2007.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. Just editiing the md file. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Ishan requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Ishan also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Ishan docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Ishan. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Ishan’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Ishan Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. Just editiing the md file. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry></feed>